<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-22T15:03:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">On the Path to Software Craftsmanship</title><subtitle>Follow along on a journey of one 8th Light Student Aprentice's path to becoming a Software Craftsman.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Setting Up Jekyll With Github Pages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/setting-up-jekyll-with-github-pages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting Up Jekyll With Github Pages" /><published>2017-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/setting-up-jekyll-with-github-pages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/22/setting-up-jekyll-with-github-pages.html">&lt;h2&gt; Intro: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was painful for a newbie… but then again, no pain…no gain! Cheesy lines aside, Jekyll is not as intuitive as it might seem from a beginners perspective. The documentation is heavy on jargon and there are multiple resources on both GitHub Pages and Jekyll, which have differing setup procedures. They do point to a great resource in Jonathan McGlone’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmcglone.com/guides/github-pages/&quot;&gt; Creating and Hosting a Personal Site on GitHub &lt;/a&gt;. Although a great resource that really allows you to personalize your page, you can bypass this tutorial to get a simple blog up and running in a matter of minutes using this quick setup guide that I have written below with the help of documentation from GitHub Pages, Jekyll, and McGlone’s tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; Setting Up GitHub Pages: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub nails it with simplicity when they explain &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt; how to create a GitHub page &lt;/a&gt;. My personal experience is that GitHub tries to take the perspective of someone who has absolutely no experience and they will guide you along the path. This is great, but sometimes it lacks that additional info for people who are like me that think…. “Why?!” My greatest weaknest is my constant urge to know the “Why.” So lets get started with this resource along with the “Why” if you are interested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Step 1: Setting up your GitHub Page with GitHub Repository: &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2017-05-22-setting-up-jekyll-with-github-pages/test.png&quot; alt=&quot;test&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Intro: Well, that was painful for a newbie… but then again, no pain…no gain! Cheesy lines aside, Jekyll is not as intuitive as it might seem from a beginners perspective. The documentation is heavy on jargon and there are multiple resources on both GitHub Pages and Jekyll, which have differing setup procedures. They do point to a great resource in Jonathan McGlone’s Creating and Hosting a Personal Site on GitHub . Although a great resource that really allows you to personalize your page, you can bypass this tutorial to get a simple blog up and running in a matter of minutes using this quick setup guide that I have written below with the help of documentation from GitHub Pages, Jekyll, and McGlone’s tutorial.</summary></entry></feed>